<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips on Gaurav Mahajan</title>
    <link>http://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~gmahajan/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips on Gaurav Mahajan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Gaurav Mahajan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/~gmahajan/tags/tips/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Few Weeks in PhD</title>
      <link>http://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~gmahajan/post/first-few-weeks-in-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~gmahajan/post/first-few-weeks-in-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post discusses the few tips recommended by people for first few weeks in PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;formulate-what-you-plan-to-work-on&#34;&gt;Formulate what you plan to work on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaguely identify in few lines the problem you are trying to solve and the research area that you plan to work/publish in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-courses-top-1020-research-papers&#34;&gt;List courses; top 10-20 research papers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List the courses that you think are relevant to your research area. Also, list top 10-20 research papers according to how relevant they are to your research area first and how many citations they have second. Discuss with your professor on what good papers and courses are missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maintain-a-diary&#34;&gt;Maintain a Diary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep a log of what you do and find daily. Make notes at multiple levels of granularity  (e.g., one sentence summary of the entire paper all the way down to sentence-level notes) from papers you read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-a-literature-review&#34;&gt;Start a Literature Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Literature Review justifies the reason for your research and allows you to establish your theoretical framework. It will also help organize the learnings from the papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-a-previous-thesis-of-the-group&#34;&gt;Check a previous thesis of the group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get an idea of who did what in your group. Learn how a PhD thesis is structured in your group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
